ratatype.com 2019-03-28

# Privacy & Terms — Ratatype

## What information do we collect?

We collect information from you when you register on our site, subscribe to our newsletter, respond to a survey, fill out a form or take a typing test or exercise.

When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your: name or e-mail address. You may, however, visit our site anonymously.

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on your site. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy.

## What do we use your information for?

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:

  * To personalize your experience (your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs).
  * To improve our website (we continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you).
  * To improve customer service (your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs).
  * To process transactions.
  * Your information, whether public or private, will not be sold, exchanged, transferred, or given to any other company for any reason whatsoever, without your consent, other than for the express purpose of delivering the purchased product or service requested.
  * To send periodic emails.
  * The email address you provide may be used to send you information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.

## How do we protect your information?

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you enter, submit, or access your personal information.

We offer the use of a secure server. All supplied sensitive/credit information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our Payment gateway providers database only to be accessible by those authorized with special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential.

After a transaction, your private information (credit cards, social security numbers, financials, etc.) will not be stored on our servers.

## Do we use cookies?

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computers hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the sites or service providers systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information.

We use cookies to understand and save your preferences for future visits, keep track of advertisements and compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may contract with third-party service providers to assist us in better understanding our site visitors. These service providers are not permitted to use the information collected on our behalf except to help us conduct and improve our business.

## Do we disclose any information to outside parties?

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

## Third party links

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

## California Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance

Because we value your privacy we have taken the necessary precautions to be in compliance with the California Online Privacy Protection Act. We therefore will not distribute your personal information to outside parties without your consent.

## Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act), we do not collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older.

## Terms and Conditions

Please also visit our Terms and Conditions section establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of our website at https://www.ratatype.com/privacy-terms/#term.

## Your Consent

By using our site, you consent to our websites privacy policy.

## Changes to our Privacy Policy

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page, and/or update the Privacy Policy modification date below.

This policy was last modified on 13.02.2019

## Contacting Us

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using the information below.

www.ratatype.com  

The following document outlines the terms of use of the www.ratatype.com website. By using and accessing this website (collectively referred to as the "Site" or "Ratatype" in these Terms of Use), you ("you", "user" or, "end user") agree to these Terms of Use (collectively, the "Terms of Service" or "Agreement").

IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THE TERMS OF THIS AGREEMENT, IMMEDIATELY STOP ACCESSING THIS SITE.

You agree not to modify, copy, distribute, transmit, display, perform, reproduce, publish, license, transfer, create derivate work from, sell or re-sell any content or information obtained from or through the Site.

## Third-party Sites

The Site may contain links to other websites maintained by third-parties. These links are provided solely as a convenience and does not imply endorsement of, or association with, the party by Ratatype.

## Modifications to this Agreement

Ratatype reserves the right to change or modify any of the terms and conditions contained in this Agreement at any time. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review the Site and these Terms of Use from time to time. Your continued use of the Site after such modifications to this Agreement will constitute acknowledgment of the modified Terms of Use and agreement to abide and be bound by the modified Terms of Use.

## Termination of Use

Ratatype shall have the right to immediately terminate or suspend, in its discretion, your access to all or part of the Site with or without notice for any reason.

## Limitation of Liability

In no event shall Ratatype or its affiliates be liable for any indirect, incidental, special, punitive damages or consequential damages of any kind, or any damages whatsoever arising out of or related to your use of the Site, the content and other information obtained therein.  
Certain jurisdictions prohibit the exclusion or limitation of liability for consequential or incidental damages, thus the above limitations may not apply to you.

## Governing Law

Any disputes arising out of or related to these Terms of Use and/or any use by you of the Site shall be governed by the laws, without regard to the conflicts of laws provisions therein.

We collect data as you use Ratatype services. What we collect, why we collect it, and how you can manage your information are described in our Privacy Policy.

Some data you can delete whenever you like, some data is deleted automatically, and some data we retain for longer periods of time when necessary. When you delete data, we follow a deletion policy to make sure that your data is safely and completely removed from our servers or retained only in anonymized form.

## Information retained until you remove it

We offer a range of services that allow you to correct or delete data stored in your Google Account. For example, you can:

  * Edit your personal info
  * Delete photo
  * Delete your Ratatype Account entirely

We’ll keep this data in your Ratatype Account until you choose to remove it.

## Data that expires after a specific period of time

In some cases, rather than provide a way to delete data, we store it for a predetermined period of time. For each type of data, we set retention timeframes based on the reason for its collection. We also take steps to anonymize certain data within set time periods.

## Date of Last Update

This agreement was last updated on February 13, 2019.
